[{"question": "What year did the Orkney Islands become part of Scotland?", "answer": "1472"}, {"question": "According to Sir Elton, what year did Paul O'Grady host his and David Furnish's stag party?", "answer": "2005"}, {"question": "In what year did Willie Nelson start out as a songwriter?", "answer": "1960s"}, {"question": "What percentage did the AfD party reach in the latest ARD Deutschland Trend poll?", "answer": "19%"}, {"question": "When did Samuel Paty get killed?", "answer": "16 October 2020"}, {"question": "What additional cost will be added to the price of a single-use drinks container in Scotland under the deposit return scheme?", "answer": "20p"}, {"question": "How much data did Kristopher and his team steal from a prominent Russian weapons-maker in January?", "answer": "100 gigabytes"}, {"question": "How much discount do students receive on Boots branded products?", "answer": "10%"}, {"question": "What percentage of phones in Turkey are Android devices according to the text?", "answer": "80%"}, {"question": "What year was Durban stripped of the hosting rights for the Commonwealth Games?", "answer": "2017"}, {"question": "According to the BMA, by how much has junior doctors' pay fallen since 2008, once inflation is taken into account?", "answer": "26%"}, {"question": "What was the magnitude of the earthquake that hit near the eastern county of Hualien in Taiwan?", "answer": "7.4"}, {"question": "According to the excerpt, what is the estimated percentage of illegal or unregulated fishing out of the total catch?", "answer": "20%"}, {"question": "How many hours was raw sewage dumped into UK rivers and seas in 2022?", "answer": "1.75 million hours"}, {"question": "What percentage of junior doctors in Scotland voted for a 72-hour walkout in the recent ballot?", "answer": "97%"}, {"question": "What did Matt Hancock suggest as a 'safer starting point' for the Covid testing period?", "answer": "10 days"}, {"question": "For how long is Paul Rusesabagina sentenced to jail?", "answer": "25 years"}, {"question": "What is the VAT rate applied to crisps made from potato?", "answer": "20%"}, {"question": "How many job cuts has Vodafone announced over the next three years?", "answer": "11,000"}, {"question": "Who is the chair of the BMA's Scottish junior doctor committee?", "answer": "Dr Chris Smith"}, {"question": "Who is the photographer of the official Coronation photographs released by Buckingham Palace?", "answer": "Hugo Burnand"}, {"question": "What year was Vaziri inducted into the WWE Hall of Fame?", "answer": "2005."}, {"question": "What percentage pay rise did teachers in Wales for the year 2022/23 accept that includes an annual pay rise and a one-off lump sum payment?", "answer": "8%"}, {"question": "According to the excerpt, what is the new bus route number that will replace route 666 to Hel in Poland?", "answer": "669"}, {"question": "Which three nuclear power plants were taken offline in Germany by midnight on Saturday?", "answer": "Isar 2, Emsland and Neckarwestheim 2"}, {"question": "What educational institution did Dame Mary gain her diploma in art education from in the 1950s?", "answer": "Goldsmiths College"}, {"question": "What pay rise did nurses, midwives and allied health professionals in NHS Scotland accept from April 2023?", "answer": "6.5% increase"}, {"question": "When did the fighting in Sudan break out?", "answer": "15 April"}, {"question": "When did the US government risk running out of money if the debt ceiling had not been raised?", "answer": "5 June"}, {"question": "How many cases of dengue has Rio de Janeiro registered so far this year?", "answer": "10,000 cases"}, {"question": "When was the last time Newcastle secured Champions League football before their recent qualification?", "answer": "2002-03 season"}, {"question": "When did Rishi Sunak order the creation of a 'NFT for Britain'?", "answer": "April 2022"}, {"question": "When did Boris Johnson receive a fine from the police for breaking lockdown rules after attending a gathering on his birthday?", "answer": "April 2021"}, {"question": "What was the record attendance at the Jerusalem Gay Pride march according to the organisers?", "answer": "30,000 people"}, {"question": "Who is the conservative leader opposing Pedro S\u00e1nchez in the general election?", "answer": "Alberto N\u00fa\u00f1ez Feij\u00f3o"}, {"question": "What is the name of the carbon capture project in Scotland that Mr. Sunak will announce funding for?", "answer": "Acorn carbon capture project"}, {"question": "Who defended the plan for juryless rape trials in Scotland by pointing to a 'weight of evidence' that juries are affected by rape myths and misconceptions?", "answer": "First Minister Humza Yousaf"}, {"question": "What specific missiles did Beijing test on 25 February?", "answer": "DF-27 hypersonic glide vehicle"}, {"question": "How long could children be detained before they can apply for bail under the new migration bill as proposed before the latest amendments?", "answer": "up to 28 days"}, {"question": "Which song did Sweden's Loreen win the Eurovision Song Contest with?", "answer": "Tattoo"}, {"question": "According to the RAC, by how much did diesel prices fall on average in the UK last month?", "answer": "12p per litre"}, {"question": "What condition was Lewis Capaldi diagnosed with that causes involuntary sounds or movements?", "answer": "Tourette Syndrome"}, {"question": "Who signed into law the bill that moved Ukraine's official Christmas Day from 7 January to 25 December?", "answer": "President Volodymyr Zelensky"}, {"question": "What was Nat Sciver-Brunt\u2019s score in the 2022 World Cup final against Australia?", "answer": "148 not out"}, {"question": "What economic growth target did China announce at the start of the NPC meeting?", "answer": "about 5%"}, {"question": "When did Atletico Madrid sign Leicy, marking a huge change in her professional experience?", "answer": "In 2019"}, {"question": "What is the deadline to apply for a Voter Authority Certificate for England's local elections on 4 May?", "answer": "17:00 BST"}, {"question": "Who is the new director general of the CBI according to the excerpt?", "answer": "Rain Newton-Smith"}, {"question": "Which two individuals were identified as high-profile figures killed in the Israeli strike according to Iran's Revolutionary Guards' statement?", "answer": "Brig-Gen Mohammad Reza Zahedi and Brig-Gen Mohammad Hadi Haji-Rahimi"}, {"question": "Which river was the first in the UK to be given bathing water status?", "answer": "The River Wharfe"}, {"question": "What must Iberian blackfoot pigs eat during the last months of their lives for the ham to be classified as Jam\u00f3n Ib\u00e9rico?", "answer": "acorns"}, {"question": "What is the maximum length of posts that users can create on the Threads app?", "answer": "up to 500 characters"}, {"question": "What percentage of reporting domestic abuse victims have experienced non-fatal strangulation according to Det Supt Lindsay Fisher?", "answer": "10-12%"}, {"question": "Who was appointed Secretary of State for Culture, Media and Sport in February?", "answer": "Lucy Frazer"}, {"question": "What specific threshold for testosterone levels did British Cycling's transgender regulations require for eligibility to compete in elite women's events?", "answer": "below five nanomoles per litre"}, {"question": "Where will the Declaration of Arbroath be on display?", "answer": "National Museum of Scotland in Edinburgh"}, {"question": "Who wrote 'The Fields Of Athenry'?", "answer": "Pete St John"}, {"question": "What position did Wrexham cement after their 3-2 win over Notts County?", "answer": "top of the National League"}, {"question": "What did Denise Gossett, her son Roman, her daughter Sabrina, and Sabrina's daughter Morgana have in common?", "answer": "all killed in the fire"}, {"question": "How much does it cost for a practical driving test in Northern Ireland?", "answer": "\u00a345.50"}, {"question": "Who will join Foo Fighters on their new tour as the new drummer?", "answer": "Josh Freese"}, {"question": "Who is the tour guide in Rome who described the conditions as 'nightmarish' to the BBC?", "answer": "Felicity Hinton"}, {"question": "Who identified Jupiter's four major moons in 1610?", "answer": "Galileo Galilei"}, {"question": "How long ago does Prof Miedzybrodzka believe the gene alteration started in Westray?", "answer": "400 years ago"}, {"question": "What specific term did Israel use to refer to the area they occupied in south Lebanon?", "answer": "\"security zone\""}, {"question": "Who was the jockey for Corach Rambler in the Grand National at Aintree?", "answer": "Derek Fox"}, {"question": "At what time did the attack on Mr. Webber and Ms. O'Malley-Kumar occur?", "answer": "shortly after 04:00"}, {"question": "What minimum hourly wage is the GMB union calling for Amazon to pay?", "answer": "\u00a315 an hour"}, {"question": "Who was the man convicted of murdering nine-year-old Olivia Pratt-Korbel?", "answer": "Thomas Cashman"}, {"question": "Who co-founded The Script alongside Mark Sheehan?", "answer": "Danny O'Donoghue and drummer Glen Power."}, {"question": "What specific action did the Commons standards committee determine Chris Pincher should face for his misconduct?", "answer": "an eight-week suspension from the Commons"}, {"question": "Who were the co-chairs of the junior doctor committee that stood on the Doctors Vote platform?", "answer": "Dr Rob Laurenson and Dr Vivek Trivedi"}, {"question": "What did Dr James Adeley, senior coroner for Lancashire, rule as the cause of Nicola Bulley's death?", "answer": "Nicola Bulley drowned after falling into cold water"}, {"question": "What maximum penalty fine did Leicester City agree to pay according to the CMA?", "answer": "\u00a3880,000"}, {"question": "Who stepped down as the SNP's chief executive after the party misled the media about membership numbers?", "answer": "Peter Murrell"}, {"question": "In what year and month did Dr. Stephen Brearey request for nurse Lucy Letby to be taken off shift after the deaths of two baby boys who were part of a set of triplets?", "answer": "June 2016"}, {"question": "What structure was the only one left standing near the hypocentre of the atomic bomb in Hiroshima?", "answer": "the Genbaku Dome"}, {"question": "How many years did the buyout of Tower extend its life according to the excerpt?", "answer": "13 years"}, {"question": "How long did Nante Niemi survive in the woods by eating snow and hiding beneath a log?", "answer": "two days"}, {"question": "How many trophies did Karim Benzema win during his time with Real Madrid?", "answer": "25 trophies"}, {"question": "How long did the same surgeon go without being tested for herpes despite being told to do so?", "answer": "three years"}, {"question": "How many times has the debt ceiling been modified since 1960?", "answer": "78 times"}, {"question": "Who declined to say who gave her the statuette but was blamed by Russian authorities for the explosion in a St Petersburg cafe?", "answer": "Darya Trepova"}, {"question": "According to the excerpt, how many homes are estimated to overheat, potentially putting those with health conditions at risk?", "answer": "4.6 million homes"}, {"question": "Who previously beat Rhun ap Iorwerth in the attempt to become party leader in 2018?", "answer": "Adam Price"}, {"question": "What percentage was the food price inflation in May?", "answer": "18.3%"}, {"question": "What is the weekly staffing cost for Erskine mentioned by Ian Cumming?", "answer": "\u00a32,000"}, {"question": "As of the upcoming second-round run-off, how many seats did the ruling AK Party and its nationalist MHP ally secure in the 600-seat parliament?", "answer": "322 seats"}, {"question": "What percentage of votes did Kemal Kilicdaroglu receive in the first round of the election?", "answer": "almost 45%"}, {"question": "What is the depth at which the five major pieces of the Titan submersible were found?", "answer": "3,800m (12,467ft)"}, {"question": "How many meetings has Apple had with the Ofcom team since April 2022 regarding the bill?", "answer": "four meetings"}, {"question": "What specific increase in pay is being requested by junior doctors to address below-inflation wage rises?", "answer": "35% pay rise"}, {"question": "Who is the UN High Commissioner on Human Rights who expressed alarm on Twitter about the detentions?", "answer": "Volker Turk"}, {"question": "What is the amount of the annual scholarship for each of the 36 black students studying at Cambridge University that Stormzy has pledged to support?", "answer": "\u00a320,000"}, {"question": "Who was the chief executive of OceanGate, the company that operated the Titanic voyages?", "answer": "Stockton Rush"}, {"question": "How many candidates are there in the Selby and Ainsty constituency?", "answer": "13 candidates"}, {"question": "What is the codename of the world's first nuclear weapon detonated by scientists in Los Alamos, New Mexico in 1945, as part of the Manhattan Project?", "answer": "Trinity"}, {"question": "How many legal firms represented those who took part in the civil damages claim settlement?", "answer": "14 legal firms"}, {"question": "What price remains unchanged for Spotify subscribers in the UK?", "answer": "\u00a35.99"}, {"question": "Who led a Red Bull one-two in qualifying at the Japanese Grand Prix?", "answer": "Max Verstappen"}]